A Guide to the Graves Mill (Madison County, Va.) Records, 1784-1886
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Graves Mill (Madison County, Va.) Records, 1784-1886
The Library of Virginia
45458
.9 cubic feet (2 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of John Y. and Dana S. Faulconer, Orange, Virginia.
Historical Information
Graves Mill was constructed in the 1790's, and supplied flour and corn products to the local community around the present day village of Wolftown in Madison County, Virginia. The gristmill was built by Thomas Graves (1733-1810). The complex also included a hemp and saw mill. Graves was also a distiller of spirits, and sold brandy. There was also a substantial blacksmith operation on site. The original mill site was constructed in 1745 by David Jones. Graves and his sons built a five-story gristmill over the foundation of the earlier mill, and in 1921, it was purchased by Silas Byron Deale, who reduced the structure to three stories.
Scope and Content
Records, 1784-1886, of Graves Mill, a gristmill located in Madison County, Virginia, and operated by Thomas Graves (1733-1810) and his sons. Includes account books, bonds, correspondence, daybook, ledgers, list of hires, orders for payments or goods, promissory notes, ticket and memorandum book, and other items.
Contents List
- Accounts and Receipts, 1785-1878. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Accounts and Receipts, n.d.. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Account Book, 1852-1856. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Account Book, 1855-1858. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Account Book (portion), 1858. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Account Book (portion), 1859-1862. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Account Book, 1869-1872. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Account Book, 1873-1876. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Account Book (Weldon J. Terry), 1879-1880. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Account Book (Rudy and Graves; Rudy, Graves and Goodman), 1883-1886. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Albert Brothers (Baltimore) Partnership Notice, 1876. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Bonds. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Checkbook, 1855. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Correspondence. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Cyphering Book (portion). (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Daybook (Beech Grove Mills), 8 August 1825 - 2 May 1826. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Estate of William Booton. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Estate of Asa W. Graves. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Estate of Thomas Hurtley. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Estate of James Jarrell. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Ledger, 1784-1802. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Ledger, 1817-1823. (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Ledger, 1828-1829. (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Ledger, 1829-1832, 1879-1880. (Box 2, Folder 14)
- List of Hires. (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Miscellaneous. (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Orders for Payment or Goods. (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Promissory Notes. (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Sale Notice. (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Subscription for School Teacher. (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Ticket and Memorandum Book, 1865-1868. (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Trade Card - William H. Smoot 1784-1802. (Box 2, Folder 22)